focusnews.com 2002-12-08

# Privacy Statement

##  Privacy Statement for Focus News 

**Focus News** has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for this Web site: [ Focus News ](http://www.focusnews.com/)

####  Information Automatically Logged 

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. _(** ELABORATE here on the purpose(s) stated above and explain here what other purposes you use the logged information for. **)_

####  Cookies 

Our Site uses cookies to deliver content specific to your interests. _(** Please elaborate on your use of cookies here.)_

####  Advertisers 

We use an outside ad company to display ads on our site. These ads may contain cookies. While we use cookies in other parts of our Web site, cookies received with banner ads are collected by our ad company, and we do not have access to this information. 

####  Registration Forms 

Our site's registration form requires users to give us contact information (like their name, email, and postal address). 

Contact information from the registration forms is used to ship purchases, information about our company. 

Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. 

####  Surveys 

Our online surveys ask visitors for contact information (like email address). 

Contact information from the surveys is used to ship purchases, information about our company. 

Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. 

####  Contests 

We run contests on our site in which we ask visitors for contact information (like email address). 

Contact information from the contests is used to ship purchases, information about our company. 

Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. 

####  External Links 

This site contains links to other sites. **Focus News** is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

####  Special Relationships 

_(** Special relationships are often very confusing, as the collection of information is often seamless to the user. Because you indicated that there are special relationships, such as "Powered by" partners, content providers, business partners, cobranded sites, then these relationships must be addressed in your privacy statement. These relationships need to be clearly defined and it must be clear who owns the information, who is receiving the information collected by the site and who has access to this information. It must be clear what type of information is shared. Is only select information shared? Is the sharing of information limited to only aggregate information? **)_

####  Public Forums 

This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

####  Security 

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. _(** Please elaborate on the security measures that you have in place. **)_

####  Children's Guidelines 

We care about children and understand that they have special privacy needs. Therefore, we have adopted the following privacy policy regarding children: 

  1. We will NOT collect, use, or distribute to third parties personally identifiable information without prior verifiable parental consent. 
  2. We will NOT give the child access to unmonitored chat rooms, message boards, email accounts, or other services that would give the child the ability to publicly post or otherwise distribute personally identifiable information without prior verifiable parental consent 
  3. When verifiable parental consent is not obtained, we will only use the online contact information (such as email) to: 
    1. Respond directly to the child's request on a one-time basis and not use that information to re-contact the child for other purposes. 
    2. Request the name or online contact information of a parent for the purpose of obtaining verifiable parental consent or providing parental notification. 
    3. Respond more than once directly to a specific request from a child (such as in the case where a child requests a newsletter subscription) and not used to re-contact the child for other purposes. We will use our best efforts to provide parental notification, which will include the nature and intended use as well as an opportunity for the parent to prevent the use of the information and participation in the activity. 
  4. We will NOT entice the child to divulge more information than is needed to participate in any activity, game, or service. 
  5. We will provide the parent a description of the specific types of a personally identifiable information collected from their child upon request. We will allow the parent to refuse further use or future online collection of personally identifiable information and provide a way for a parent to obtain any personally identifiable information collected from their child. 
  6. We will provide notice to children in age appropriate terms of what personally identifiable information is to be collected. 
  7. We will NOT provide any links to Web sites that are unsuitable for children. 
  8. We will encourage children to get their parent's permission before sharing personal information online. 

####  Choice/Opt-Out 

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving promotional/marketing information from our partners, and us . 

  1. You can send email to [ webmaster@focusnews.com ](mailto:webmaster@focusnews.com)

####  Data Quality/Access 

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided: 

  1. You can send email to [ webmaster@focusnews.com ](mailto:webmaster@focusnews.com)

##  Contacting the Web Site 

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact:
